Guide to the Jeff Zenick Comix and Small Press Collection 1984-2003
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Jeff Zenick Comix and Small Press Collection
1984-2003
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
SC 003.7
Zenick, Jeff, 1956-
1.75 linear feet of shelf space 4 boxes
This collection consists of small press literature and comic books donated by underground writer Jeff Zenick. The collection includes approximately 200 underground comix and homemade zines, spanning four decades, in the small press/underground genre. Some of the subject matter is controversial, and contains violent and/or sexual themes.
Jeff Zenick was born in 1956 to American parents living in Paris. When he was two years old, he and his parents relocated to the Washington, D.C. suburbs in Maryland. In several interviews, Zenick credited his troubled childhood and teenage years with sparking his love of drawing. After graduating from high school in Maryland, he traveled extensively through the United States, drawing (mostly portraits, nature and urban scenery) and working odd jobs to support himself. As of 2015, Zenick resides in Tallahassee, Florida and is still very active in the small press community, appearing at conventions and selling his art in a variety of brick-and-mortar stores and online.
These underground comix and small press materials were collected by Jeff Zenick and were published circa 1984 to 2003. The collection includes 95 unique titles, with sequential issues of many comix, newsletters, and zines. Standard and digest size comix make up about fifty percent of the collection and most are underground and small press comix with amateur production values and small print runs. Minicomix are approximately ten percent of the collection. Approximately forty percent of the collection is non-comix related, consisting of advertising and promotional materials, catalogs, newsletters, and zines (a term derived from "magazine," and self-published via photocopier). Of these, zines are a small majority (about ten percent of the collection) and are notable for their representations of the American music underground, counterculture, horror and fantasy writing, and several works by Jeff Zenick.
This collection is arranged in six series. All material in each series is arranged alphabetically by title.
Series 1: Advertising, Promotional Material, and Catalogs. This series contains materials related to the advertising and promoting of comix, zines, comic books, promotional comix-related events, and catalogs for comix, comic books, anime, art supplies, and other related materials.
Series 2: Books. This series contains published novels with sci-fi and fantasy themes.
Series 3: Comix. This series contains two subseries based on format: Subseries 3.1: Standard and digest comix, and Subseries 3.2: Minicomix.
Series 4: Magazines and Comix Related Materials. This series contains professional-quality published material in magazine format, and a variety of materials relating to comix and comix creators.
Series 5: Newsletters. This series consists of newsletters of small press and library groups and organizations.
Series 6: Zines. This series consists of small press zines written by one or multiple authors.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Jeff Zenick donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries (MS.2009.20).
Steve Willis Underground Comics Collection, 1966-1997 (SC 003.1)
Lynn R. Hansen Underground Comics Collection, 1899-1994 (SC 003.2)
Paul Brians Comics Collection, 1950-2004 (SC 003.3)
Steve Willis Comix and Small Press Collection, 1968-2004 (SC 003.4)
Clark Dissmeyer Comix and Small Press Collection, 1977-2002 (SC 003.5)
Joseph M. Shea Comix and Small Press Collection, 1967-2010 (SC 003.6)
Comic Art and Culture Collection 1969-2009 (SC 003.8)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Comic books, strips, etc.; Graphic novels; Underground press publications; Underground comic books, strips, etc.; New wave comics; Erotic comic books, strips, etc.
Publishers and Publishing.
- Series 1: Advertisements, Promotional Material, and Catalogs
  - Expo Fan Zines 6a, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Brad W. Foster Checklist, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Global Gazette, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series 2: Books
  - Black Snow Days, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Let Out the Beast, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Comics
  - Subseries 3.1: Standard and Digest Comics
    - 365 Women. Numbers 6 and 9, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Amoeba Adventures Fifth Anniversary Special, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Amused to No End, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Assassin and the Whiner. Number 2, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Astronaut Hair, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baby Sue, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Barefoot and Pregnant. Number 4, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bread and Water Tales. Number 2, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Broken Funder, volume 2, number 1, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bubonix. Numbers 1, 23, 24, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - The Catbox Room. Number 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Collier's. Number 4, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Ditch, The River, The Sea, The Snake, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Fishin', 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Freaks at the Counter, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Fred, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Gato Bazka, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - The Global Gazette. Number 1-3, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Glorianna, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Gorilla Cookies, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Horseback Salad, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hysteria Action Forum. Number 5, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - ISIS, an Historical Art Journey, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Jennifer Daydreamer. Number 8, 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - JKC World Tour Book 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Joy and Spider. Number 6, 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Kuba sin Embargo!, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Laugh, Clown, Laugh, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Led Balloons, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Most Powerful Gate, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Mr. Mike's Lucky. Number 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Natch, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Neighborhood Treat Comics. Number 3, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - New Love. Number 5, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - No Fun Comics. Number 2, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Not My Small Diary. Number 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - One Normal Guy Talking With a Nut!, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Out of the Blue!. Numbers 3 and 4, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Penny Century. Number 1, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Rumbling Underneath. Numbers 0-2, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - S and Em Presents. Number 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - The Sands 1-3, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Silly Cat. Number 1, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Silly Daddy. Numbers 13-16, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Silverfish, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Smartest Kid on Earth, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Social Skills. Numbers 2 and 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Stanley Stinkbug. Number 2, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Storeyville, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Take Care, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Top Shelf. Numbers 1-4, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Velvet Comics, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Wheelbarrow. Number 4, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Wodaabe Comics. Number 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - World War 3. Number 24, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Zippy. Number 17, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Subseries 3.2: Minicomix
    - 5 o'clock shadow. Number 13, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Babylon Mystery Drawings, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Damn Weird. Number 6, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Death of Antisocialman. Number 10, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Election Headquarters, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The Fifth Book of Neds and The Sixth Book of Neds, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - In der Nacht die Welt Dreht Sich das Oberste Zuunterst (In the Night the World Spins from the Highest to the Lowest), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Ivin: A Man and His Wafer, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Junk. Number 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Last Rites, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Minty Comic. Numbers 3 and 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - My Summer Vacation. Number 2, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - My Worst Fear, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Smiley's Really Weird Comic and Smiley's Totally Strange Comic. Numbers 1 and 2, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - The Story of Vasilia and Baba Yaga, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Ten Thousand Things (Thinks). Numbers 3, 5, 12, 26, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series 4: Magazines and Comix Related Materials
  - Natural Born Students: A Book of Postcards, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Comics Journal. Numbers 193, 194, 196, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Comics Journal. Numbers 197 and 198, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series 5: Newsletters
  - Horizons Unlimited. Numbers 69-74, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Scavenger's Newsletter. Number 215, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Poopsheet. Numbers 14-16, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Skeet's Fan Forum and Review. Number 10, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Series 6: Zines
  - Bull Dada volume 3. Number 5, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - The Catbird Seat. Number 6, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Cotyledon. Numbers 6 and 10, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Cross Currents. Number 21, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Destined. Number 2, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - JOMP Jr. Numbers 21 and 22, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lunatic Chameleon. Number 3, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - O Fanzine Das Xornados, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Recycled Jokes by Frog, 1990-1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - T.R.'s Zine. Number 14, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Typical Studies. Number 3, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - White Buffalo Gazette, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)